<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Learning Notes</title>
    <link>https://riamf.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Learning Notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 11:54:05 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://riamf.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Grafana in docker setup</title>
      <link>https://riamf.github.io/posts/dockerized_grafana_setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 11:54:05 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://riamf.github.io/posts/dockerized_grafana_setup/</guid>
      <description>Grafana Grafana is a tool that lets you visualize metrics. It handles a lot of different data sources and is very flexible. It does not require you to be an it expert to setup and with just few easy steps you can connect to your database or service and present live metric that can help you more deeply understand how your system is used. With a system of alerts it tell you about bottlenecks that you might not know of, like moments in time when your system is overloaded and you database is dying.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Estimates of variability</title>
      <link>https://riamf.github.io/posts/estimates_of_variability/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 16:08:06 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://riamf.github.io/posts/estimates_of_variability/</guid>
      <description>Deviations The most widely used estimates are based on differences in data, deviations, like observation and given estimate of location. Take for example this set {1,2,3}. Mean equals 2 and deviations are:
1. 2 - 1 = 1 2. 2 - 2 = 0 3. 2 - 3 = -1  This deviations tell us how dispersed observations are around the central value. What is also interesting is that the sum od deviations from the mean value equals 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metrics and estimates</title>
      <link>https://riamf.github.io/posts/metrics_and_estimates/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 18:47:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://riamf.github.io/posts/metrics_and_estimates/</guid>
      <description>Mean Most basic estimate for location. As simple as possible it is just and average value from a list of values described with equation:
$$ \frac{\sum\limits_{i=1}^n x_i}{n} $$
Trimmed Mean It is a small variation of mean. Fist Values are sorted, then some number of values are dropped from collection beginning and end. After that normal average value is computed. It is Very useful when we want to eliminate the influence of extreme values in data set.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://riamf.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://riamf.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Here is my site where I keep my notes projects and blogs.
Thanks for reading!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>